London, United Kingdom (+44) 7783602996 azfar.ghazian@gmail.com

Ghazian Azfar

Software Engineer

GitHub: ghazian Portfolio Site LinkedIn: ghazian

Software Engineer experienced in developing customer-focused applications and user-centered solutions with intuitive design. Currently building real-time sports data dashboards and visualizations for SaaS products, spanning front-end and back-end services.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Go

Databases PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, Redis / AWS Elasticsearch

Back End Kubernetes, Django, Docker, AWS, Terraform (IaC), GraphQL, WebSockets, REST API

Test Jest, Testing Library, Playwright

Web Development React, MUI, NextJS, TypeScript, Styled Components, Node. is, Remix, Zustand, Zod, Redux

Skills Clean Code, Extreme Programming, CI/CD (Github Actions) & Accessibility

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mid Software Engineer

IMG Arena

Jan 2024 — Present

London, UK

- Developed and maintained a real-time, data-driven web platform showcasing over **1000+ live sports events globally**. Designed scalable solutions utilizing **WebSockets** for low-latency updates and **REST APIs** for data retrieval.
- Introduced design principles to create reusable components, ensuring consistent UI/UX design standards across 2 product lines. This improved the overall design and made it easy for team members of all skill levels to compose and extend components.
- Developed the company's first data and table visualization package, which includes a suite of customisable widgets and themes. This package is now used throughout the organization and externally.
- Designed and implemented high-performance APIs in **NodeJS**, optimizing server-side data processing and achieving a **50**% decrease in data retrieval speeds, along with API documentation in **Docusaurus** library.
- Successfully implemented and deployed **Redis** as an in-memory caching solution for heavy API calls and **PostgreSQL** for static data **reducing response times by up to 200%**.
- Mentored and onboarded graduate team members through a mentor buddy program, facilitating their integration into the team.

Junior Software Engineer IMG Arena

Jul 2022 — Jan 2024

London, UK

- Leveraged Kubernetes health checks and Datadog metrics to ensure the **resiliency and reliability** of microservices. Created Datadog dashboards to monitor application health and configured monitors for alerts.
- Actively wrote tests, integration/unit with Jest and E2E tests with Playwright and Mock Service Worker (MSW), I also wrote our
 test environment through MSW, mocking WebSockets, GraphQL, REST API responses.
- Implemented state management in our React application to streamline network performance, resulting in a 40% decrease in latency across thousands of WebSocket messages, GraphQL and REST API integrations, ensuring a seamless user experience.
- Developed the applications **CI/CD**, ensuring that every branch on the latest commit triggers continuous integration for tests, UI deprecation, and network health.

Consulting Intern

Deloitte

Sept 2018 — Dec 2018

Jakarta, IDN

- Created a Python script to assess workflow documents and extract vital metrics resulting in a 2-hour reduction in work.
- Facilitated workshops with VP/Manager level to uncover pain points and potential use-cases of the transformation program.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science, *University of Glasgow* | *Aggregate 2:1*Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science, *University of Binus* | *Aggregate 2:1*

Jan 2021 - Jan 2022 Sept 2015 - Jan 2020

PROJECTS

BIG DATA CORESET CONSTRUCTION IN K-MEANS PROBLEM

Jan 2022

• Created a lightweight coreset construction for K-Means problem along with 3 algorithms based on the works of [1][2][3], to reduce the amount of space time complexities machines currently use when clustering K-Means problem of large data sets. **Platforms** - Python, NumPy, Matplotlib (data visualization), Pandas, Shell Scripting and Tensor Flow.

Other Projects include - Real time bike sharing web application with Flask; Using Artificial Intelligence to play Flappy Bird using Neural Network and Genetic Algorithms.